Finding Aid for Ann Arbor Young Men’s - Young Women's Christian Association (Mich.) records, 1894-1956
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor Young Men’s - Young Women's Christian Association (Mich.) records 1894-1956
Ann Arbor Young Men’s - Young Women's Christian Association (Mich.).
2 linear feet and 1 oversize folder
851787 Ba 2; UBAm
Minutes of board meetings, membership and treasurer's records, scrapbooks, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by the organization (donor no. 3698 ) in 1960.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The earliest records of the Young Men's Christian Association do not mention its founding date. The Woman's Auxiliary to the Young Men's Christian Association was formed in 1894. According to the organization's website, the men's association was probably founded in 1883. The two groups merged in 1957.
The record group includes minutes of meetings, membership materials, and treasurer's records of the Young Men's Christian Association dating from 1902 to 1933. The history of the women's association is documented in greater detail with minutes and scrapbooks, dating back to 1894 and extending to the mid-1950s. There is very little material from the 1950s on.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
African Americans--Children.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor Young Men's-Young Women's Christian Association (Mich.); Camps--1941-1950.; Children.; Children playing with marbles.; Clothing and dress.; Costumes.; Handicraft.; Pageants.; Parties.; Recreation.; Sports.; Women--Organizations.
Contributors:
Young Men's Christian Association (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Young Women's Christian Association (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Young Women's Christian Association records
  - Minutes of regular meetings, 1910-1917 (Box 1)
  - Board of Director's minutes, May 1898-1915
    - May 1898-March 1905 (Box 1)
    - 1910-1915 (Box 1)
  - Membership records, 1894-1918
    - 1894-1908 (Box 1)
    - 1916-1918 (Box 1)
- Young Men's Christian Association records
  - Membership records, January 1902-1933
    - January 1902-1914 (Box 1)
    - December 1914-December 1921 (Box 1)
    - 1922-1933 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's records, 1905-1909 (Box 2)
- Other records
  - Minutes of YMCA, Women's Auxiliary
    - 1894-1904 (Box 2)
    - 1910-1920 (Box 2)
    - 1926-1931 (Box 2)
  - Loyalty Club records
    - 1910-1912 (Box 2)
    - 1917 (Box 2)
  - Y Girls Club records, 1912-1922 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1902-1955, 4 volumes and 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 3 folders (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Building interiors, 1945-1946 (Box 2)
  - Camp Birkett and Summer Fun Club, 1940-1956 (Box 2)
  - YWCA activities, 1914-1928 (Box 2)
    (also 1 item in oversize folder, UBAm)
  - Miscellaneous, 1897 and 1938-1956 (Box 2)